{
    "id": "bc164c39cffa436498c21ed98013fcb6",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "You must not question .............................. does not concern you.",
            "description": "What means that which.",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "03b5569425a74b5b92cad919ff69d980"
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister reads .............................. she gets some free time.",
            "description": "Both when and whenever are possible here, but whenever is more emphatic. ",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "whenever",
                "whatever"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "224590f940864b43990cb69a0eb7d705"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ria is confident ............................ she will win the race.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "708ce2a3434744d896a1d88f83cb3c18"
        },
        {
            "question": "You have to decide ........................... subject you want to study.",
            "description": "Which and what are often both possible with little difference of meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "which",
                "Either which or what"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "365261dc6d48474e91ab1f0a8396eaec"
        },
        {
            "question": "Aunt Polly suspected ........................ Tom was playing some tricks on her.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'that' can connect the main clause to a subordinate noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "71644b02d84a457d96167b91354c09d6"
        },
        {
            "question": ".............................. she was behaving so strangely was not clear to us.",
            "description": "The question word why indicates reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "That",
                "Why",
                "What"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1bf4197350a94d6b824c99f6dc51802d"
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandmother can only walk slowly ........................ she has arthritis.",
            "description": "So indicates the result because indicates the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "because",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "44db433d4e8a4c57a804db8045dcc774"
        },
        {
            "question": "......................... it tried very hard, the cat could not climb the tree.",
            "description": "All of these conjunctions have the same meaning. Even though is more emphatic.",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "Though",
                "Even though",
                "All of these"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "c5750cc17c5345ec89d165429ff35b48"
        },
        {
            "question": "........................... you are determined you can succeed in whatever you do.",
            "description": "Whether cannot be used to indicate a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "Whether",
                "If",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b3cbda3c50714b51be8f3151b9725004"
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked ........................ I could help him.",
            "description": "Both if and whether can be used to introduce an indirect question. ",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2cbfa568f0b848ac9c9528801425001b"
        },
        {
            "question": "She waited in the park .......................... her friends arrived.",
            "description": "Unless means if not. Until indicates time.",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0c540ff97c424b2a960bacb9f25af71f"
        },
        {
            "question": ".......................... you give me the keys of the safe, you will be shot.",
            "description": "Unless indicates a condition. It means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Until",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "582473bea66a4925a64b79598199fa31"
        }
    ]
}